# Bharathi Kannan V

#### **Full Stack Developer**

A seasoned IT professional with a stellar professional background leading all aspects of Sofware Development, Strategic Planning, and Operational Management.

bharathikannanv05@gmail.com

+919443470347

Coimbatore, India

www.bharathikannan.com



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Lead Experience Engineer**

Publicis Sapient 🗷

03/2023 - Present

Bangalore

Achievements/Tasks

- Frontend Lead: Responsible for building accessible web applications with React, Javascript, HTML and CSS.
- Full-stack developer with a primary focus on UI development.

## **Software Engineer**

Twilio 🗷

10/2022 - 02/2023

Bangalore

Roles and Responsibilities

 Responsible and Accountable for the development, and delivery, of multiple services powering Studio. A low-code tool for building applications.

#### **Technical Lead IV**

Photon Interactive

05/2020 - 10/2022

Chennai

Roles and Responsibities

- Application lead managing a team of 2 Frontend engineers and 3 QA resources.
- Architect Lead to analyse and develop POCs for upcoming features in product.

#### **PROJECTS**

Marketer Dashboard (11/2023 - Present)

- Leading a team of three in UI development to manage evolving client requirements efficiently.
- Enhanced developer productivity through integrated tools for linting, formatting, and unit testing. Implemented Storybook for isolated component development and testing. Established comprehensive documentation outlining coding standards and best practices.

# Studio - A Low Code Application Builder (10/2022 - 02/2023)

 Analyzed and developed local environment setup to build UI quickly. This drastically improved the development experience which made us ship changes rapidly.

### Clinical Trials Web Application (05/2021 - 10/2022)

 Involves creating and using clinical forms to get data from patients, which involves complex calculations and branching logic.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Engineering**

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College

2012 - 2016

Coimbatore

Specialization

 Computer Science and Engineering

#### **SKILLS**



## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Just Javascript Certification by Dan Abramov (03/2023)

The course consists of 10 modules in which we explore the Javascript universe and build our mental model from the inside. Learned about primitives of Javascript and understood how objects work under the hood.

#### Joy Of React Certification by Josh Comeau (03/2023) 🗷

Workshop-based React course provided by Josh Comeau. Learned about best practices for developing web applications with react. Understood Component API design.

#### Epic React Certification from Kent C. Dodds (03/2021)

Workshop-based advanced React course provided by Kent C. Dodds and egghead.io. Learned about all the parts in web development with React from developing, styling, testing, and measuring the performance of a production application.

#### Front-End Web Development with React (03/2020)

Completed the course with 100% Grade provided by The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology through Coursera

#### Certified Full Stack Engineer (03/2019)

Provided by National Institute of Information Technology and Sponsored by Cognizant Technology Solutions

#### EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

An overall experience of 8 years in Web Application Development, UI Design, and Web-based technologies (04/2016 - Present)

4 years of experience in SPA development with TypeScript, React, Redux, Next JS, Amazon Web Sevices, DynamoDB, Firebase, Cloud Firestore, Apollo GraphQL, Material UI, HTML, SCSS, and CSS. (03/2019 - Present)

Exploring trending technologies and tools like RSC, Remix, Next JS, Chakra UI, XState, CSS-In-JS and Interested in contributing to Open-source tools, and Writing blogs.

# **INTERESTS**

Phones Technology Blog Open Source